A Guide to the Scott County (Va.) Records, 1782-1951, undated
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Scott County (Va.) Court Records, 1782-1951, undated
The Library of Virginia
0007283687-0007283689, 0007283663-0007283666, 0007550954, 1011980, 1011985, 1011989-1011990, 1011996, 1050470, 1050485-1050487, 1050491, 1050503-1050505, 1050507, 1050514, 1050516-1050525, 1050527-1050531, 1050534, 1093159, 1161981-1161983, 1161985
1 v.; 36 boxes and 7 folders (30.53 cu.ft.)
Scott County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court papers from Scott County under the accession number 50083.
Item (Militia Fines, 1828, photocopy) in Box 1050470 came to the Library of Virginia under the accession number 34832. Original item is found in Box 1137318.
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court records from Scott County.
Historical Information
Scott County was formed from Lee, Russell and Washington counties by a statute adopted on 24 November 1814. The county court first met on 14 February 1815. Scott County was named for General Winfied Scott, a native of Virginia, in recognition of his victories during the War of 1812. General Scott was later commanding general of the American army during the war with Mexico.
Scope and Content
Scott County (Va.) Records, 1782-1951, undated, consist of Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, County Administrative Records (including Board of Supervisors, Commissioner of Revenue, Overseer of the Poor, Sheriffs' and Treasurer Records), Court Records (County, Circuit and Unspecified), Election Records, Fiduciary Records, Health and Medical Records, Justice of the Peace Records, Land Records, Marriage Records and Vital Statistics, Military and Pension Records, Miscellaneous Records, Organization Records, Public Buidings and Grounds, Road and Bridge Records, School Records, Tax and Fiscal Records and Wills.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Scott County Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm" found on the Library of Virginia's web site.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Scott County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records--Virginia-- Scott County.
Geographical Names:
Scott County (Va.)--History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia-- Scott County.
Contents List
- Registers of Births, 1874, 1876, 1800-1884
- Registers of Births, 1885-1887, 1890-1891, 1895
- Registers of Deaths, 1874, 1880, 1882-1887, 1890-1891
- List of Applicants for Pensions on File in the office of the Circuit Court Clerk, 1902 July 1
- Confederate Pension Applications, 1902-1905
- Confederate Pension Applications, 1906-1908, 1912-1914
- Board of Commissioners of Pension Reports and Lists, 1902-1913
- Records, 1830-1941 circa
  Military and Pension Records: Militia Roll, 1855; School Records: Cedar Grove School House Trustees' Report, 1896; Court Records: Court Fees, 1830-1865 circa, Judgments, Executions, Commonwealth Causes, 1880-1941 circa., Miscellaneous Bonds, 1890-1933; Health and Medical Records: Lunacy papers, 1934
- Records, 1886-1897
  Treasurers' Records - School Fund Settlements, 1887-97; Board of Supervisors' Records - District Road Funds, 1886-87
- Records, 1865-1948
  Tax and Fiscal Records: Lists of Delinquent Lands, Assessments, Reassessments, Erroneous Assessments(1883-1932); Land Records: Surveyors' Reports and Accounts(1865-1948); Miscellaneous Records: Crop Liens(1945-47.)
- Records, 1872-1932
  Court Records: Warrants, Funds, Accounts(1888-1902); Accounts Allowed-Paid(1872-94); Jury Summons, Commonwealth Causes(1927-32.)
- Records, 1895-1910
  Bonds-Commissions-Oaths: Miscellaneous Bonds and Oaths(ca. 1905-07); Court Records: Executions(1895-1910)
- Records, 1866-1930
  Court Records: Executions, Petitions, Orders(ca. 1920-1930); Fiduciary Records: Administrators' Accounts(1866-1898)
- Records, 1782-1875
  Tax and Fiscal Records: Merchant's License Receipt, 1812, Tax receipts for delinquent lands, 1817, 1820, Tax Receipt, 1840s; Bonds-Commissions-Oaths: Oaths, 1864, Officials' Bonds, 1815, 1819; Court Records: Executions, 1819, 1826, 1838, Subpoenas, 1864, 1866, 1875, Commonwealth Causes, 1862; Suit settlement (unidentified and undated); Fiduciary Records: Hire of negroes - A. M. Gray estate, 1863; Land Records: Deed, 1831; Tax receipts for delinquent lands, 1817, 1820; Miscellaneous Records: Confederate Currency, Powers of Attorney, 1869; Miscellaneous receipts, 1863, 1864, 1871; Military and Pension Records: 1782 (copy from Montgomery County), Militia fines, 1828 (Photocopy - Original found in Scott County Chancery Records - Kane vs. Fugate and others, 1847-005, Box 1137318). Accession number 34832. Chancery related records pulled and placed with Scott County Chancery Records collection.
- Records, 1821-1942
  Court Records: Civil Executions, 1893-1897, Civil warrants returned, 1887-1910, Civil Executions, 1860, 1893-1905, Warrants, 1823-1833, List of sales of property on executions, 1831-1833; Criminal Records: Executions, 1824-1899, Commonwealth warrants, 1887-1901, 1922-1923, Arrest warrants, 1941-1942; Sheriffs' Records: Reports, 1896-1898; Tax and Fiscal Records: County claims, 1821-1867. CHANCERY PULLED.
- Records, 1815-1901
  Bonds/Commissions/Oaths: Commissioners and testimonial, constables, school commissioners; Court Records: forthcoming, prison, indemnify; Fiduciary Records: Guardians' Bonds; Tax and Fiscal Records: Ordinary License Bonds.
- Records, 1815-1899
  Bonds/Commissions/Oaths: officials', politicians, ministers'; Fiduciary Records: administrators, executors, curators.
- Records, 1815-1903
  Court Records: Recognizance, Commonwealth and Certificates, Replevin, Attachment; Fiduciary Records: Committee Bonds; Tax and Fiscal Records: Liquor License Bonds; Land Records: Deeds A-Z [1817-1849.]
- Records, 1839-1947
  Land Records: recorded deeds "W"; Court Records: Criminal records, warrants, judgment related records; Fiduciary Records; Papers were found in Deeds series.
- Records, 1815-1917
  Court Records: Judgments, 1815-1876, Rules 1864-1877, Judgments certified, 1903, Rules and subpoenas before the grand jury, 1884-1887, County Court subpoenas, 1860-1917, Commonwealth Grand Jury subpoenas and jury lists, 1879-1899, Criminal records, 1815-1885; Board of Supervisors' and Road and Bridge Records, 1868-1885; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths: Loyalty oaths, 1882. CHANCERY PULLED.
- Records, 1818-1924
  Tax and Fiscal Records: County and Commonwealth Claims, 1860-1923, Papers related to delinquent and forfeited lands sold, 1836-1880, 1873; Merchant interrogatories, 1923-1924; Court Records: Executions, subpoenas, summons, writs, etc. 1825-1890 ca., payments of jurors, 1860-1870, Ejectments, 1860, Criminal Records: Reports of criminal cases, 1888, Indictments, 1860-1877, criminal related papers, 1850-1880 ca.; Promiscuous papers (contains deeds, executions, land grants, plats, etc.) 1818-1875, Jury list, 1871; Bonds/Commission/Oaths: Loyalty oaths, 1861-1893; Election Records: Certificates of registration, voter lists, 1904-1914, abstracts of votes, 1872-1886; Land Records: Deeds, 1832, 1840, 1885, Copies of deeds, 1858, 1888; Miscellaneous Records: Powers of Attorney, 1885; Fiduciary Records: Sales [estate], 1874-1932, Guardian papers, 1859, 1867, 1869, 1870, Settlement of estates, 1857-1871, Inventories and appraisements, 1858, 1862, 1863: Board of Supervisors' Records: 1868, 1869, 1873, 1874, 1886, 1887, 1923; Marriage Records and Vital Statistics: Marriage Licenses, 1854-1899 (9 items); Military and Pension Records: Militia fines, 1836. CHANCERY AND JUDGMENTS PULLED.
- Records, 1815-1934
  Record Series: Court Records: Schedules of insolvent debtors; Health and Medical: Lunacy papers; Fiduciary Records: Auditor reports; Miscellaneous Records: Certificates of estray; Road and Bridge Records and Board of Supervisors' Records: Road reports and warrants; Land Records: Land grants and surveys, various reports.
- Records, 1821-1914
  Sheriffs' Records: settlements of sheriff (county funds), 1821-1867; Tax and Fiscal Records: articles of agreement, 1830-1852; claims allowed, 1828-1838; claims allowed on county levy, 1834-1838; receipts of licenses, 1845-1853; Treasurer's Records: settlements of Treasurers, 1905; Overseer of the Poor: certificates of Overseers of the Poor, 1824-1848; Land Records: reports of surveyors, 1860; Board of Supervisors' Records: road accounts, 1912; Health and Medical: lunacy papers, 1902; 1912-1914; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths: oaths of office, 1893-1899; Court Records: Commonwealth's rules discharged, 1889-1903; list of suits from circuit court, 1892-1902. UNPROCESSED
- Records, 1817-1913
  accounts, estate papers, reports, birth and death records, road reports, school reports, notices of candidacy.
- Records, 1819-1914
  Court Records: Schedule of insolvent debtors, Judgments: Attachments and bonds; Military and pension Records: Militia officers commissions; Board of Supervisors: Claims allowed; Miscellaneous Records: Certificates of Estrays; (Oaths of office); Tax and Fiscal Records: License reports, etc.
- Records, 1842-1951
  Court Records: Judgment related papers, 1875-1903, Subpoenas and jury lists, 1861-1886, Clerks' Records: Correspondence, 1950-1951; Tax and Fiscal Records: License tax list, 1893-1924, Personal Property Tax Interrogatories, 1875, 1894, County and commonwealth claims, 1856-1860, Delinquent land taxes, 1870-1877; Treasurer Records, Reports, 1898-1899; School Records: School Commissioners reports, 1842-1860; Marriage Records and Vital Statistics: Register of Births and Deaths, 1890; Miscellaneous Records: Miscellaneous accounts, 1919 and Overseers of The Poor Records: Superintendents of the Poor Reports, 1872, 1920, 1921
- Records, 1815-1932
  Court Records: Criminal Records: Pardons, 1898, Court Finance: Fee bills, 1893-1899; Health and Medical: Lunacy Papers, 1908-1910, 1916-1917; Overseers of the Poor: Reports and Orders, 1815-1850; Board of Supervisors' Records: Map of road from Pattonsville to Fairview, map of C. C. & O. Railroad and Company, and other maps, 1929, Road Maintenance reports, 1926-1927; Tax and Fiscal Records: Claims allowed, 1922; Commissioner of Revenue: License Reports returned by Commissioner, 1913-1914, Merchants and other licenses, 1906-1916, 1920-1921; Justice of the Peace Records: Magistrate Reports, 1930-1932; Military and Pension Records - Militia/regimental returns, 1830-1853 ca. CHANCERY AND JUDGMENTS PULLED.
- Records, 1843-1939
  Court Records: Ejectment cases determined at August term, 1873, Orders for Writ of Prohibition - 1843, wrappers, blank court papers, clerks' records- 1906-1922, jury payments, 1868, grand jury proceedings, 1872; writs of possession, 1881-1887, Criminal records: Indictments, 1872, Presentments, 1846; Tax and Fiscal Records: Tax receipts, 1876-1877, County and commonwealth claims, 1878-1916, State Personal Property Interrogatories, 1893-1894, 1897, Liguor license tax lists, 1890-1891, Barroom bonds, 1883-1884; Election Records: Blank certificates of registration, 1870; Overseers of the Poor, 1878-1881, Miscellaneous Records: Works Progress Admininstration Historical Surveys, 1939; Organizational Records: Pamphlet - One hundredth anniversary of Methodist Missionary Society, 1919 (contains a road map of West Virginia, Virginia, and Maryland; Board of Supervisors' Records, 1872-1891, County Road Warrants, 1933; Fiduciary Records: Estate settlement papers, 1860's ca. CHANCERY AND JUDGMENTS PULLED.
- Records, 1820-1933
  Court Records: Debt notes, 1848-1879, Criminal Records: Indictments (also includes judgments), 1825-1877, Commonwealth vs. Daniel Dean murder case, 1879; Tax and Fiscal Records: County and Commonwealth Claims, 1845-1869, 1922, Licenses other than merchants, 1922-1923, Report of merchants' licenses, 1924-1925; Board of Supervisors Records: Warrants, 1931-1933, Road warrants, 1886-1890; Marriage Records and Vital Statistics: Birth certificates, 1912-1913; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths: Oaths, 1861-1874; School Records: School statements, 1880-1883, School warrants, 1924. CHANCERY PULLED.
- Records, 1815-1933
  Court Records: Abstracts of judgments, summons, subpoenas, warrants, criminal papers, etc. 1825-1917, Ejectments, 1866, 1870; Board of Supervisors' and Road and Bridge Records: Papers re: right of way, 1904, Road maintenance reports, 1932, Road papers, 1815, 1823, 1868-1887, Expense and payroll reports, 1921-1922, Road commissioner reports, 1914-1916, District road warrants, 1932-1933; Treasurer Records: Reports, 1911, 1918, Various warrants (county, school, etc.), 1899-1900; Officials' appointments/oaths/bonds, 1850, 1866-1885, Loyalty oaths, 1873-1874; Tax and Fiscal Records: Reservations of title to personalty, 1910-1920 ca., Inventory of ardent spirits, 1917-1919; Land Records: Abstract of deeds related to lands in Wise County, 1891, Election Records: Lists of voters registered since 1919, Abstract of votes, 1875; Fiduciary Records: Settlement of Estates, 1864-1870, Inventories and appraisements, 1860-1870, Administrator Bonds, 1865-1871; Marriage Records and Vital Statistics: Marriage returns, 1840-1864. CHANCERY AND JUDGMENTS PULLED.
- Records, 1826-1921
  arrest warrants, subpoenas, state tax tickets, fiduciary, executions, oaths of office, certificates of candidacy, road accounts.
- Records, 1860-1931
  summons, personal property tax lists, settlement papers.
- Records, 1871-1931
  settlements of estates, indictments, delinquent land, personal property interrogatories, accounts allowed, birth and death registers, public building and grounds, jail inspector reports.
- Records, 1852-1939
  guardians bonds, delinquent land and Capitation, warrants, etc.
- Records, 1874-1942
  assessor bonds, guardians' bonds, supervisor bonds, school vouchers and warrants, personal property interrogatories, delinquent property lists.
- Records, 1848-1911
  indictments, reports, delinquent land lists, road reports, state personal property interrogatories, partition of estates etc.
- 1852-1935
  Court Records: Subpoenas, 1874-1875, Criminal Records: 1852, 1872, 1893, Commonwealth vs. Worley Ramey, 1917; Clerks' Records: Clerks' Finances, 1929; Tax and Fiscal Records: Tax assessment lists, 1912, 1918, County claims, 1870, 1881-1882, List of Delinquent lands, 1870-1872, 1885, 1907, Personal property tax interrogatories, 1894, 1897, Tax tickets, 1890, 1893; Public Buildings and Grounds: Receipt book - Repair Work on Courthouse; Lunacy Papers, 1906-1935.
- Records, 1871-1942
  state and personal property interrogatories, delinquent lands, auditors reports, bills presented to board of supervisors, license reports.
- Records, 1840-1921
  Delinquent Lands sold to the commonwealth and others, Personal Property and Capitation Taxes
- Records, 1871-1898
  Volume consists of the following record series: Report of County Levy, 1871, pp. 1-8; Record of Personal Fiduciaries, 1875-1881, 1887, 1890-1898, pp. 10-15; Will, 1884, pp. 222-223.
- Records, 1799-1935, undated
  Military and Pension Records, 1814-1886, undated (includes Application for Artificial Limb); Justice of the Peace Records, 1818-1860, undated; Fiduciary Records, 1881; Land Records, 1799-1935, undated; Court Records, 1815-1874; Marriage Records and Vital Statistics, 1859-1928.
- Records, 1822-1927, undated
  Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, 1826-1904, undated; Commissioner of Revenue Records, 1886; Election Records, 1831-1927, undated; Tax and Fiscal Records, 1822-1915, undated.
- Records, 1813-1911, undated
  Court Records, 1819-1899, undated; Health and Medical Records, 1847-1884; Miscellaneous Records, 1813-1911; Overseer of the Poor Records, 1816-1873; Public Buildings and Grounds, 1823-1892, undated; Tax and Fiscal Records, 1824-1902, undated; Wills, 1847-1895, undated.
- Road and Bridge and Board of Supervisors' Records, 1817-1901